On Monday, index funds
will have to buy 16
million shares worth
of Reddit, whether they
want to or not.
Here's why.
Reddit beat earnings
on July 30,
but the stock fell
around 12.5%.
Two weeks later, though,
a committee added
it to a list and then
it rose 15%.
Because now, roughly
a third of the US stock
market is run by funds
that are contractually
forbidden to have, like,
an opinion.
The buyers are
a Vanguard, iShares,
Fidelity, and Schwab.
This is because Reddit
is joining the S&P 500.
So joining the S&P
is usually treated
as a stamp of approval
for your company.
Obviously, when
a company joins
the index, its stock
will temporarily bump
up.
But over the long run,
there's been a study
done where they use
a three-year event
window.
They found that added
stocks actually
underperformed by a wide
margin.